maplewood.com 2017-12-02

# Maplewood Computing Privacy Statement

 At Maplewood Computing Ltd. (“Maplewood”), we are committed to protecting the confidentiality, security and accuracy of the personal information we receive about you. The management of personal information is fundamental to our service and this Privacy Policy explains our approach to honouring this commitment. 

This Privacy Policy outlines the Principles and guidelines by which Maplewood operates to protect the personal information of individuals that we collect, use, disclose and retain in the course of our operations, as subject to the provisions of the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) and applicable provincial privacy legislation. 

As you browse this website, www.maplewood.com, personal information may be collected if you provide it when registering for a service, submitting a question, requesting more information, submitting a resume or any other request for information. This personal information is used only for the purpose for which you intended and will not be released to anyone else. If you have a request that was submitted to Maplewood instead of your school/board/district contact, we may, at our discretion, forward your request to the appropriate person in your school/board/district. 

We will not sell, rent, or release personal information to third parties. Any usage information will be compiled in a way that protects individual personal information. 

As you browse this website, our servers automatically collect the following information for traffic monitoring and statistical purposes: 

  * Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of the computers being used to access our sites; 

  * the operating systems and the types and versions of browsers used to access our sites; 

  * the dates and times users access our sites; 

  * the pages visited; 

  * the 3rd party sites you link to from our site. 

Maplewood reserves the right to block access to and from inappropriate internet domains, email addresses or websites. 

If you watch videos from our website, YouTube automatically collects statistical information such as number of views, date viewed, length of time watched, number of shares, viewing device, gender and country of viewer. 

The information collected from our website servers and from Youtube may be used to help improve our website. We cannot link this information with the identity of individuals visiting our website. 

As you browse www.maplewood.com, for convenience, there are links to other websites such as social media sites and other companies that provide third party integration services for our clients. Links to other third party sites are not governed by this Privacy Policy. Although we endeavor to link only to sites with high privacy standards, our Privacy Policy will no longer apply once you leave our website. We are not responsible for privacy policies employed by other parties. We suggest that you examine the privacy policies of those sites to learn how personal information may be collected, used and/or disclosed. 

If you are a staff member of a “client” (school/board/district/authority/agency/institution using Maplewood’s products or services) with authorized access to Maplewood’s customer collaboration site, information that you enter on the site will be recorded in Maplewood’s support tracking application. The support tracking application records your questions and problems, and a ticket number is assigned associating the client with the information you entered. This entered information is confidential information between Maplewood and the client, and is used to help answer your question or resolve your problem. There is the ability for Maplewood clients to “share” the contents of tickets with other Maplewood clients outside their educational authority, and this feature should only be used if no personal information will be disclosed. Maplewood is not responsible if personal information is shared by a client, however, we reserve the right to unshare any ticket. 

If you are a staff member of a “client” with authorized access to Maplewood’s support services, we will collect the following personal information so that we can communicate with you about our services, including informing you about product and service updates, and responding to your support or other inquiries: 

  * name;

  * job title;

  * contact information (work phone numbers and emails).

Clients using Maplewood’s data hosting service (cloud hosting) should note that our servers automatically collect the following information for traffic monitoring and statistical purposes: 

  * Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of the computers being used to access our sites;

  * the operating systems and the types and versions of browsers used to access our sites;

  * the dates and times users access our sites;

  * the pages visited;

  * email addresses for those people designated as Authorized Contacts for the purpose of providing an initial verification that the person requesting a change is authorized to do so.

Maplewood reserves the right to block access to and from inappropriate internet domains, email addresses or websites.

This information is used to help improve our hosting service. Please note that we are able to link this information with the identity of individuals using this service. 

Clients who have provided authorized access to Maplewood connectEd to staff, students, and parents/guardians should note that the following information is collected for the purpose of providing an audit trail that changes are being made by people authorized to make said changes: 

  * the specific identity of a user, when they logged on and off,  and the computer being used to access Maplewood connectEd;

  * if the client is using Maplewood’s data hosting service,  Maplewood also collects the pages visited and if changes are made to data, the specific data that is changed is also tracked. 

Maplewood’s clients collect, use and disseminate personal information from, and about, individuals in the course of providing educational services. Each client will have its own privacy policy regarding the information that may be used or disclosed by the client. All data collected by the client remains the property of the client. Creating and supporting student information applications is Maplewood’s core business. Maplewood may be granted access to the client’s data for the purpose of supporting, maintaining and enhancing Maplewood’s products and services as required by the client. 

Maplewood Computing Ltd. is responsible for personal information under our control and is committed to a high standard of privacy for our information practices. This Privacy Policy incorporates the ten principles set out in the National Standard of Canada’s Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information, CAN/CSA-Q830-96. 

### Principle 1 - Accountability

Maplewood is responsible for personal information under our control, including personal information transferred to third parties for processing. Maplewood has designated an individual who is accountable for the organization’s compliance with this policy. 

Maplewood complies with PIPEDA by: 

  * implementing policies and procedures to protect your personal information, and all other confidential information including information relating to students, parents/guardians, emergency contacts, and school/board/district staff and affiliates;

  * responding to complaints and inquiries;

  * educating our staff about privacy policies and practices.

### Principle 2 - Identifying Purposes for the Collection of Personal Information

Maplewood will identify the purposes for which personal information is collected at or before the time of collection. Unless the new purpose is required by law, the consent of the individual is required before information can be used for that purpose. 

Personal student/staff/affiliate information under our control but collected by the school/board/district will be subject to that school/board/district privacy policy. Persons collecting personal information should be able to explain to individuals the purposes for which the information is being collected. 

### Principle 3 - Consent for the Collection, Use, and Disclosure of Personal Information

Maplewood will obtain the consent of individuals before or when it collects, uses, discloses and retains personal information, except where authorized by law. 

### Principle 4 - Limiting Collection of Personal Information

Only the information necessary for the purposes identified may be collected. Maplewood will collect personal information by fair and lawful means. 

### Principle 5 - Limiting Use, Disclosure, and Retention of Personal Information

Personal information may be used only for the purposes for which it was collected, except with your consent or as required by law. The information is retained only as long as necessary for the fulfilment of those purposes. 

### Principle 6 - Ensuring Accuracy of Personal Information

Maplewood will make every effort to ensure the information we hold is accurate, complete and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used. 

### Principle 7 - Ensuring Safeguards for Personal Information

Maplewood applies security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of personal information to aim to protect it against loss, theft, unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use, or modification, regardless of its format. 

The nature of the safeguards will vary depending on the sensitivity of the information that has been collected, the amount, distribution, and format of the information, and the method of storage. Protection may include physical measures (i.e., locked filing cabinets and restricted access), organizational measures (limiting access on a "need-to-know" basis), and technological measures (use of passwords, encryption and audits). 

New staff are required to complete privacy and confidentiality education and sign a confidentiality agreement as a condition of employment. Contracted staff are bound to privacy and confidentiality as a condition of the contract. All new staff and contracted staff have criminal record checks and vulnerable person screening. Care is used in the disposal or destruction of personal information, to prevent unauthorized parties from gaining access to the information. 

### Principle 8 - Openness About Personal Information Policies and Practices

Maplewood will make readily available to individuals specific information about its policies and procedures relating to the management of personal information. The information made available shall include: 

  * the name or title, and the address, of the person who is accountable for the organization’s policies and practices and to whom complaints or inquiries can be forwarded;

  * the means of gaining access to personal information held by Maplewood;

  * a description of the type of personal information held by the organization, including a general account of its use. 

Contact information for Maplewood’s Privacy Officer, to which complaints or inquiries can be forwarded, is provided in Principle 10. 

### Principle 9 - Individual Access to Own Personal Information

On written/email request, and subject to the exemptions stipulated by law, Maplewood will inform individuals of the existence, use, disclosure and retention of their personal information and provide access to that information. An individual will be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate. In certain situations, Maplewood may not be able to provide access to all of the personal information that it holds about an individual. These situations shall be limited to those required or stipulated by law. 

### Principle 10 - Challenging Compliance with the Privacy Policies and Practices

An individual will be able to address a challenge concerning compliance with the above principles by contacting Maplewood’s Privacy Officer. Maplewood has procedures in place to receive and respond to complaints or inquiries about their policies and practices relating to the handling of personal information. Maplewood will investigate all complaints. If a complaint is justified, Maplewood will take appropriate measures, including, if necessary, amending their policies and practices. Individuals will be able to obtain more information on Maplewood’s privacy practices, or make a complaint, by contacting Maplewood Computing's Privacy Officer. 

### Privacy Officer

Maplewood Computing Ltd.

1971 Mallard Rd.

London, ON N6G 5L8

Email: [privacy@maplewood.com](mailto:privacy@maplewood.com)
